George A. Caldwell papers, 1966-1984
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
George A. Caldwell papers, 1966-1984
MS 289
Caldwell, George A. (George Allen), 1912-
Chiefly typescript drafts of his published and unpublished historical studies of New Mexico and Texas, including Across Texas in Poetry, Frontier Military Posts of New Mexico, History of Luna County, New Mexico, and New Mexico and the Southwest. Also includes an account of Pancho Villa's 1918 raid at Neville Ranch, Texas, by Lois Neville Kelly.
1.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
George Allen Caldwell was born in 1912, attended college in Texas, and spent most of his career as a secondary school teacher of History in New Mexico. He taught in the Deming school system from 1959 until his retirement in 1974.
Scope and Content Note
Chiefly typescript drafts of his published and unpublished historical studies of New Mexico and Texas, including Across Texas in Poetry, Frontier Military Posts of New Mexico, History of Luna County, New Mexico, and New Mexico and the Southwest. Also includes an account of Pancho Villa's 1918 raid at Neville Ranch, Texas, by Lois Neville Kelly.
Access Terms
Villa, Pancho, 1878-1923
Caldwell, George A. (George Allen), 1912- -- Archives
United States -- Army -- Military life -- History
Freemasons -- Deming Lodge No. 12
Spanish mission buildings -- New Mexico
Church buildings -- New Mexico -- Torrance County
Frontier and pioneer life -- New Mexico
Saline Missions (N.M.) -- History
Texas -- Poetry
Mexico -- History -- Revolution, 1910-1920 -- Sources
New Mexico -- History -- 1848-
Texas -- History -- 1846-1950
Luna County (N.M.) -- History
Fort Cummings (N.M.) -- History
Neville Ranch (Tex.) -- History
Drafts
Illustrations
Poems
Container List
- Biographical information. No Date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Speech: Deming High School graduation. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Across Texas in Poetry. No Date (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Frontier Military Posts of New Mexico. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Geographical Background of New Mexico. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- History of Deming Lodge 12 A.F. and A.M. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- History of Luna County, New Mexico. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
- History Scribblins. 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Just a Bit o' Me. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Last Retreat: The Story of Fort Cummings. 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Last Retreat (continued). 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- New Mexico and the Southwest. ca. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2-8)
- Saline Missions. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- An account of Pancho Villa's raid on Neville Ranch, Texas, March 25, 1918, by Lois Neville Kelly. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)